Good Morning, Church.
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers, thank you for your time.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Today, we’ll talk about how to be filled with the Holy Ghost as a Christian.
If Christians need to be filled with the Holy Ghost; how?
That is the question.
How?
HOW TO BE FILLED WITH THE SPIRIT
It is a core and fundamental area of the Gospel – to be filled with the Holy Ghost
because you cannot do anything for God, as far as God is concerned,
you cannot represent God, be involved in God’s projects without the Holy Ghost.
He who sees Him sees the Holy Ghost.
You cannot be a Christian without Him.
You know Jesus – you know the Holy Ghost.
This is why today we say, ‘Christians’ and ‘true Christians’.
It means there are Christians and there are also true ones.
In every area of life, there are fake; there are true.
Which one are you?
For several years I have been experiencing an encounter in this area,
going by what we are seeing every day in the ministry here.
This is an apostolic ministry - not just a ministry, but an apostolic ministry.
So, several years of experience and encounter.
I am going to share with you my personal experience, supported with the Holy Bible.
Referring you to those areas in the Bible -
my personal experience I'm going to share with you.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
I am not going to say much about baptism of water, which is a human act.
When you are OK, they will just usher you for that baptism.
So, today, we will use Apostle Peter.
We are not going to go deep on baptism of water, but the Holy Ghost.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
We have many books to support this,
but I will take my proof reading from the Book of Acts 10 - that will be my proof reading.
The other Book you have is John 14:26 - that will really help you.
And 1 Corinthians 12:1 – end.
That will really help.
And 1 Corinthians 2:13.
And Romans 14 about this issue of faith;
anything that does not come from faith is sin - Romans 14:5 - end.
And the Book of Colossians 3, and Ephesians 5 - that will help.
When you get home, take those Books, listen to the message.
Hallelujah.
Take the Book about 7 sons of Sceva - Acts 19:13.
OK, thank you.
Are you there?
Hallelujah.
So, let's take the Book of Acts 10.
Cornelius called for Peter - I'm just taking reading from verse 1.
“At Caesarea there was a man named Cornelius, a centurion
in what was known as the Italian Regiment.
He and all his family were devout and God-fearing;
he gave generously to those in need and prayed to God regularly.”
So, let's take our proof reading there - verse 44.
“While Peter was still speaking these words, the Holy Spirit came on all who heard the message.
The circumcised believers who had come with Peter were astonished
that the gift of the Holy Spirit had been poured out even on Gentiles" -
that is unbelievers; people they were not expecting that this could reach, be poured on.
“For they heard them speaking in tongues"
We will talk about all this today.
“For they heard them speaking in tongues and praising God. Then Peter said,”
‘Surely no one can stand in the way of their being baptized with water.'"
Like I told you, the baptism by water is a human act; take note of that.
“’They have received the Holy Spirit just as we have’.
So he ordered that they be baptized in the name of Jesus Christ.
Then they asked Peter to stay with them for a few days.”
Why should Peter have stayed with them for a few days?
For counselling, for guidance, for the purpose.
You have several Books here today, which are going to help you.
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
Christians must be filled with the Holy Spirit.
You must be filled with the Holy Spirit to be a Christian.
No one can do the work of God without the Holy Spirit.
Doing it without the Holy Spirit is tantamount to taking huge affliction, trouble, pain.
The Bible says that not everyone who says "Jesus is Lord" will do things with the help of the Holy Spirit.
You can say, do and preach, without the help of the Holy Spirit
but you will find that you are inflicting pain, wounds, harm on yourself.
So, let's quote Peter.
While Peter was speaking, the Holy Spirit fell on the hearers.
What does that mean?
It means it fell on those who believed,
on those who prepared for the Holy Ghost,
meaning that God owned Peter’s words and bore witness to Peter’s words.
In other words, he was sent by God Himself.
That is the evidence to show he was sent by God Himself.
It was not Peter - it was a representative, an ambassador.
I will take you one by one, like I have told you - I'm going to share my encounter with the Holy Ghost,
so that it will be easy for you.
If I'm talking about what is in the Bible alone, it may seem to be difficult for you, but let's go.
Yes.
To be prepared for the Holy Ghost - "I want to be baptized, I really want to be filled with the Holy Ghost."
The step you are going to take:
Listen to me with all your heart.
You must listen to me with all your what?
- Heart.
The heart that holds grudges, offence, pain of the past – this is where your problem comes from.
Everyone here holds one offence or the other.
Unforgivingness - everyone here.
Viewers, listen to me:
Everyone holds one offence or the other.
You are claiming your rights, "How can I be cheated, insulted? Why?"
Whether you are cheated or not, offence is a crime to God.
Listen to me with all your heart but not a heart that holds offence or pain of the past.
But you are holding offence.
In the process of claiming your right, you are holding offence.
That is why it will be difficult for you to have my message with all your heart.
You will hear, you will see me as a lecturer...
In the school you hear, and it will go into your what?
Mental assent?
You receive it but not in your heart.
To receive the message with all your heart, your heart must be free.
Heart means man’s spirit.
How many of us have a free heart here today?
Heart that does not hold grudges, offence, heart that has nothing to do with yesterday,
whatever happened, unless the one that glorified God.
This is where you are!
This is why it will be difficult for you to listen to me with all your heart.
I'm sharing with you how you can be baptised,
how you can be filled with the Holy Ghost.
Listen!
You must listen to me with all your heart – a heart that does not hold offence.
Speak to yourself in Psalms in your heart as you are listening to me.
There is no neutral heart. You can't say, "Hm, I don't want to talk".
If you don’t want to talk, your heart will talk.
Something is going on.
Don’t allow your spirit to take hold of you; you control it.
"I must control you. While I'm listening to T.B. Joshua, I must control my heart."
Speak to yourself in Psalms, hymns and spiritual songs,
making melodies in your heart to God.
But how many hearts now are engaged in those...?
A lot of things are going on in your heart.
"What is going to happen today?"
Don’t allow your heart to control you.
As a Christian, speak to your heart in Psalms, hymns and spiritual songs.
Make melodies in your heart.
That is how to receive.
By the time you get hold of your heart, you are about to be filled.
You cannot get hold of your heart; your heart is jumping up and down.
A lot of things are going on, "My business. Let me look at my time."
That is why sometimes you don't need to go to the restroom, the diabetes you are talking about.
It is because you are not getting hold of your heart.
When your heart is jumping, "I have not gone to the toilet today"
- immediately you have the sense of going to the toilet.
"I have not eaten today" - immediately you have the sense of eating.
"I have not made a call to my brother today" - immediately you receive a call.
The real battle is in our heart.
For - against.
If you can control your heart, get hold of your heart, the sky is your limit.
Tell your neighbour,
If you can get hold of your heart, the sky is your limit.
You leave your heart; you are looking at me and your heart is free to say whatever it wants to say.
Don't allow that!
As you are looking at me, take hold of your heart.
"Take more of me, give me more of You; more of Your faithfulness, kindness, goodness..." -
a lot of Bible Psalms, hymns, melodies.
"Jesus, Jesus..." - that alone is OK.
"Jesus, Jesus..."
"Jesus, locate me in Your mercy."
Give your heart assignments.
If you don’t give your heart assignments, your heart will look for assignments.
"Oh, look at that hair-style. Look at that dress.
Look at that beautiful woman. Look at that handsome man.
This church - there are a lot of changes. Oh my God."
Your heart will be roaming about.
If you don't give a message to your heart, your heart will be just doing whatever,
"Look at the fruit; will I have one today? What is going to happen? Oh, this church is beautiful.
Oh, look at this man; I like his suit - I think I can get it.
I saw one jeep at the car-park today; I think I'm going to make a photo of this jeep."
Your heart keeps roaming about; this is what is putting you in trouble.
This is what will distance you from God.
This is why you are not filled with the Spirit.
Talk to your heart!
Keep your heart busy; get hold of your heart!
This is my life.
When I'm going, I will not even know that you are passing me, because I'm busy in my heart.
You think that because I am not talking I am not busy - I am busy.
Sometimes, when I watch TV, a football game...
You think that I'm watching football; only my eyes are watching but my heart,
"Take more of me, give me more of You. Lord".
By the time I say, "Jesus!" - maybe someone is wounded on the field -
it means what I'm saying is what I...
Or when I'm sleeping, my nature is to keep my heart busy.
I give my heart a job, not my heart giving me job.
Your heart is giving you job.
When I'm sleeping - you think I'm sleeping; it is only my body.
Come and attack me.
I say, "Jesus!"
But you, "Honey!"
Which honey?
Can honey help you?
Your honey will say, "What has happened, dear?"
"Don't worry, these people."
Some will say, "Leave me!"
"What is happening? Honey, what is wrong?"
The name of Jesus is "leave me" - this is the life you are living.
Even when you are inside a vehicle, and the car is about to get an accident;
in the process of somersaulting, "Honey, Honey!"
Can your honey help you?
Because you are not used to it.
At the end of the day; maybe you are trapped, they are giving you food in the dream,
or the accident has happened, you say, "Jesus!"
It has happened already - why are you calling Jesus?
Hallelujah!
Yes.
Don't forget our message today.
HOW TO BE FILLED WITH THE SPIRIT
The Word and the Spirit are inseparable; that is, intimately linked together.
The Word and the Spirit - you cannot separate these.
You cannot just come and say, "Jesus!"
By what authority are you calling Jesus?
The Word and the Spirit are intimately linked together.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you want to live, talk, smile, sleep, eat in the Spirit, keep in the Word,
live in the Word, abide in the Word and become totally saturated with the Scripture.
You will find yourself overflowing with the Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour,
If you want to live in the Spirit, that is, to be filled with the Spirit,
living in the Spirit is living with Jesus.
Sleeping in the Spirit is sleeping with Jesus.
Eating in the Spirit is eating with Jesus.
Tell your neighbour,
If you want to live in the Spirit, keep in the Word, abide in the Word,
become totally saturated with the Scripture and you will find yourself overflowing with the Spirit.
Not just flow, but overflowing with the Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I may take you back again, because I don't want this message to just go.
I'm not a lecturer, I'm just telling you the message God has given me to tell you.
What is going on in your heart now?
Madam, as you are sitting, you must take control of your heart.
If you don't take control of your heart, your heart will be jumping up and down.
You will see someone who put a wig on there, someone who is talking there,
someone who is shouting there, someone...
You will be looking at T.B. Joshua, "Oh, this is a beautiful attire".
Take hold of your heart.
Now, continue to speak to your heart in hymns, in psalms,
"The Lord is my Shepherd, I shall not want. Take more of me, give me more of You."
A lot of things, messages, spiritual songs in your heart, make melody in your heart to God,
"Thank You, Lord... Jesus Christ... Locate me in Your mercy..."
Keep busy in your heart.
Before you know it, you will start speaking in tongues, you will find yourself in another realm.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Not only here.
When you are at home, when you are eating, "Locate me in Your mercy..."
When your heart is talking, your lips cannot move - I'm just telling you what your heart will engage in.
"Locate me in Your mercy. Take more of me." - you have to engage your heart.
That is the prayer.
The prayers you are offering today are not prayers.
The real prayer is engaging your heart, "Take more of me, give me more of You" - that is the prayer.
But the one you offer, "Lord Jesus - thank You, Lord..." - that is not prayer, you are speaking to yourself.
That is why your prayers are not answered.
The real prayer...
When you begin to engage your heart, you will not go where Jesus will not be welcome.
You will not say what Jesus would not want you to say.
I want to ask a question.
When did the Spirit move?
It was when Peter started speaking that the Spirit began to move.
Before I will go further; I hope you have captured how to be filled?
Have you captured it?
Your heart, I repeat again,
keep your heart; get hold of your heart.
You allow your heart to continue to throw you into problems and afflictions,
throwing you over this, diabetes, this, that, thinking about that - no!
Speak to your heart.
You see me going; I'm engaging my heart, "Thank You, Jesus".
I'm telling you now what I engage my heart with.
"Thank You, Jesus..."
I'm saying, "Thank You, Jesus" in my heart, but my lips - no one knows.
If you call me, I will answer you, I will greet you, because it is my heart that is engaged, "Thank You, Jesus".
If somebody just comes out to attack me, that attack Jesus will... - He will defend me.
You always wait for an attack, before you call Jesus.
You always wait for the situation, before you call Jesus.
You always wait for a time when you need Him, before you call Him.
Tell your neighbour,
You don’t know how much you need Him.
I cannot heart you.
I cannot hear you.
You don’t know how much you need Him.
Me? - I don't wait for anything.
As I'm walking, "Locate me in Your mercy...", but my lips are OK, you cannot know.
That's why sometimes, when you call me, "Good Morning, sir",
I don't answer promptly because I'm busy.
If you call me, when you engage with me on the phone, "Hello!",
you think I can't hear what you are saying; I hear, but because my heart is engaged -
"How are you? Where are you now? OK, I'm in the church."
Because I'm screening your voice to know who is talking - whether it is ogbanje or witchcraft.
Voice is more powerful than anything.
OK, last Sunday you saw what happened.
I stood here and I began to say, "In the name of Jesus...", out there you saw people vomiting,
coming out, pool of blood, menstruation, fibroid, everything - you saw it.
Voice - it is voice!
At home, all over the world people are getting delivered by mere looking at me, listening to me.
So, this handset...
They get you proper there.
Not everybody listening to me is going to be filled with the Holy Ghost.
Going by what we have read in Acts 10:44,
not everybody listening to me is going to be filled with the Holy Ghost.
I would not want you to come and kneel down and ask God to fill you
when you are not prepared.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I would not want you to come and kneel down and ask God to fill you
when you are not prepared
because the Holy Ghost is not received by everyone, only those who are prepared for Him.
And I have told you about the preparation, which you have received today.
Get hold of your heart.
Speak to yourself in Psalms.
Speak to yourself in hymns.
Speak to yourself in spiritual songs.
Make melodies in your heart to God.
Colossians 3, Ephesians 5 - you will find it there.
I would like to have you meditate on the Scriptures.
The more you meditate on what you read in the Bible,
and turn it over and over again in your heart,
the more your heart acts upon the Word.
Turn it over and over again in your heart.
Tell your neighbour, "Turn it over and over again in your heart."
You know what I mean?
It is like you are pounding yam; turn it over...
The more your heart, your spirit acts upon the Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Acts upon the Word.
It’s not just to read.
Read!
Turn it over and over again in your heart, what you read;
the more your heart acts upon the Word.
If you are not grounded in the Word,
there will be nothing for the Spirit to hold on.
In the Book of John 14:26 it says,
there will be nothing for the Spirit to remind you of.
That is John 14:26.
It must remind you of: thou shalt not kill, thou shalt not destroy, thou shalt not this, thou shalt not that.
If you are not grounded in the Word of God, there will be nothing for the Spirit to remind you of:
thou shalt not kill, thou shalt not...
If there is nothing...
The Spirit will be released to the extent, measure, degree
we stand in reverence, in honour of His Word.
I repeat again.
The Spirit of God will be released to you to the extent, measure, degree
you stand in reverence, in honour of His Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How do you honour His Word?
You say, "Jesus must be honoured...in my life every day".
They are talking about His Word.
Jesus and His Word are one.
The Spirit will be released to you to the extent, degree, measure
you stand in reverence, honour of His Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Before you can be filled with the Spirit, you must be sure that you can.
Tell your neighbour,
Take note of that.
Secondly, before you can be filled with the Spirit, you must desire that.
You read so much about the Spirit of God.
You read about an accommodation that you need to prepare for the Spirit of God.
What is the accommodation?
What He wants, what He doesn't want - put those things together.
Put your home in order.
If your home is in disarray, disorder - you must think how to arrange your home before He comes.
Before you can be filled with the Spirit, you must be sure that you can.
I'm telling you my personal experience of several years and supporting it with the scripture for you.
If I now go into the Scripture, begin to tell you when I'm not filled,
definitely, it would be difficult for you to understand.
That is why what you are reading over and over, everywhere, you cannot practice.
Are you sure that you want to be possessed by a Spirit?
Are you sure that you can be possessed by a Spirit?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This Spirit is like Jesus.
There are two kinds of spirit possession.
Evil spirit possession, where the human personality is taken over -
making them filthy, dumb or evil as we can see them being delivered or cast out today.
The Holy Spirit wants to possess us Christians.
Tell your neighbour.
The Holy Spirit wants to possess us Christians
because there is no way you can be a Christian without the Holy Ghost.
The Holy Ghost wants to possess us Christians.
This Spirit is like Jesus.
Are you ready to be possessed by a Spirit that is like Jesus?
Ask your neighbour.
I cannot hear you.
Are you ready to be possessed by a Spirit that is like Jesus?
You know Jesus – you know the Holy Spirit.
If truly you know Jesus, are you ready to be possessed by a Spirit that is like Jesus?
I know Jesus – I know the Holy Spirit.
Tell your neighbour.
If truly you know Jesus, you know the Holy Spirit.
Because we are not sure; truly, we don't know Jesus.
You say you know Jesus and you don't know the Holy Spirit -
it means you don't know Jesus.
You say, "I know Jesus", but you don't know the Holy Spirit -
Many people say they are Christians; they are not Christians, they are religious people.
You say you are a Christian.
If truly you are a Christian, you know Jesus, and if you know Jesus, you know the Holy Spirit.
But here, I can't see the Holy Spirit in the life of people.
You know Jesus?
You know the Holy Spirit.
Truly, if you know Jesus, you know the Holy Spirit because they are inseparable,
intimately linked together.
It is when one is filled with the Spirit, then you can be baptised.
But you are not filled with the Holy Spirit and you are now going for a baptism -
you can never be filled with the Holy Spirit.
That is the challenge you are facing.
You say you are not a graduate, you never attended university,
but you bought a certificate that you have 2nd class upper.
Can you now go back to the university?
That is the problem you are facing.
Tell your neighbour,
Because you have been baptised by water, it is difficult for you to be filled with the Holy Spirit.
Because things are in ascending order, but now you are taking descending order.
You know you are not filled with the Spirit, but you are now being baptised.
You can tell your pastor, "Pastor please, I'm not filled with the Holy Spirit. Don't baptise me; it's a curse".
Can't you hear what Peter said, "We cannot stop these people from being baptised by the water
because they are filled".
Are you with me?
If you are not a graduate and you bought a certificate which says you are a graduate,
and you say you have 2nd class upper and you are now working,
can you now turn around and say, "I'm going to the university"?
Will they not query you about the certificate you have?
So, the same way, you are baptised in the water;
can you now turn around and say, "I need the Holy Spirit now"?
Unless you are delivered.
Say, "I need deliverance".
Deliverance of what?
Of water baptism.
You need deliverance?
Deliverance of what?
- Water baptism.
Even to say it out, it is difficult for you.
Deliverance of what?
- Water baptism.
You have been baptised with the water.
Double...
Overhauling.
Oh my God.
Yes, we are on the way to the filling.
After this message, I know you will know the way out now.
The way out has come.
Halleluja!
If you claim to know Jesus and you don’t know the Holy Spirit, you are deceiving yourself.
What is the role of the Holy Spirit?
A Spirit – pure, sane, gentle, wise, loving – for that is exactly what He is like.
A Spirit – pure, sane, gentle, wise – for that is exactly what He is like.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Holy Spirit is pure – He is the Holy Spirit.
He is wise for He is the Spirit of Wisdom.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He is true for He is the Spirit of Truth.
He is like Jesus for He is the Spirit of Christ.
He is like the Father for He is the Spirit of the Father.
This Spirit wants to possess you.
This Spirit wants to be your Lord
so that you will no longer be in control
of the little vessel in which you sail - your body.
You know, I'm the one sailing this one - this is a little vessel.
He wants to be in charge and take over from me because without Him, I will not be able to stand;
I will not be able to be pure, wise, loving, gentle.
He wants to take control of this little vessel and sail it by Himself.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you sure you want to be possessed by the blessed Spirit of the Father and Son?
Because you often like to be in charge – founder, general overseer.
“I want to do this today, another tomorrow”,
whereas God owns our future.
Do you want your personality to be possessed by Someone who is like Jesus?
Tell your neighbour.
Again, ask your neighbour.
Do you want your personality to be possessed by Someone who is like Jesus?
Again.
Again and again.
Do you want your personality to be possessed by Someone who is like Jesus?
I cannot hear you.
Do you want your personality to be taken over by Someone who is like Jesus?
You will not wake up and say, "Yes, help me iron these three suits.
I will wear this one on Monday, this one on Tuesday, this one on Wednesday"; as if you are God.
How do you know that you will see tomorrow?
Tell me.
We are in the world; you have seen so much.
People say, "I will see you tomorrow" - the next thing you learn is that person is in the graveyard.
Do you want your personality to be taken over by Someone who is like Jesus?
If you want that, begin to see today as if it is your last day on earth.
I cannot hear you.
If you want your personality to be taken over by Someone who is like Jesus,
right now, begin to see now as if it’s your last day on earth.
Now, begin to see today as if it’s your last day on earth.
If you see today as if it is your last day on earth - you know;
all those things you keep somewhere...
There are poor people on the street; instead of sharing with them, helping them, you promise this or that...
This is all propaganda.
How do you know?
Begin to see today as if it’s your last day on earth
if you want your personality to be taken over by Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you are not filled with the Spirit, you cannot obey the written Word.
Let me show you.
You see it?
Let me see your own.
Raise your own up.
Say to yourself.
If I am not filled with the Spirit, I cannot obey the written Word.
This is why all what you are reading here is like literature to you.
It is just mere literature.
You read to preach, to teach; you don't read to live in it.
You cannot live it; you cannot read what is here, if you are not filled with the Spirit.
You can preach, you read it to teach it, to preach it, to counsel people,
but to live in it, you cannot because there is no way you can.
If you don’t obey the Scripture, you quench Him.
Can you see the importance of the Spirit?
If you don’t obey the Scripture, you quench Him;
you are not a Christian, irrespective of your knowledge in the Bible.
If you are not filled with the Spirit of God, you cannot obey the Word of God
because the holy men were carried along by the Spirit as they were writing the Word.
It is not a literature, it is not something you can put here.
You can memorize it, you can keep it in your mind - but to keep it in your heart, no way without the Spirit.
I want to leave you.
Can you give me your word?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can somebody answer this question?
How will you be filled with the Spirit?
Can somebody?
Because without the Spirit of God you cannot obey the written Word.
You are not filled with the Spirit and you are carrying the Bible.
Tell your neighbour,
The Bible you carry is not only a Bible; there is a Bible and there is Holy Bible.
The Bible is history, events that happened to apostles and God's generals,
but the holy, it has to do...
OK, can somebody answer this question?
How will you be filled with the Spirit?
OK, give it to my brother.
By meditating upon His Word.
What are you meditating on?
The Word of God.
- Are you doing that now?
- Yes, sir.
- Now, now, now?
Can you tell us what are you meditating on?
Psalm 28:7.
- As you are looking at me?
- Yes, sir.
- Even as you are talking to me?
While you are talking to me, you cannot stop your meditation.
Meditation is a thing of the heart; it is different from thinking.
Thinking is lower level; upper level is meditation.
Meditation has to do with Heaven, knowledge of Heaven
but thinking has to do with your challenges.
When you say, "Ha, how will I get out of this mess now?", you are thinking.
"How will I sleep now?" - you are thinking.
"Oh, I don't know what is wrong." - you are thinking.
That thinking leads to depression.
When you are meditating, you can answer people, you can talk to people.
You can greet people while you are meditating.
Let me hear from my brother.
- You mean you are meditating now?
- Yes, sir.
- As you are talking to me?
And when this thing becomes part of you, over the time, then your blood and fluids will cooperate.
Right now at the beginning, your blood will not cooperate.
You know, blood cooperates - when you move, the blood flows,
but right now, when you begin, your blood will not cooperate.
You will find it difficult - the beginning of everything is like that.
When you wanted to start crawling when you were a baby...
You were an embryo - see what you have become today.
This is why we give you faith bracelets.
Who has a faith bracelet here?
Oh yes - come on, bring your own.
This is why we have this.
It helps you to meditate.
Unlike religious people - when they have it, you see their mouth...
It is for meditation to reset your belief.
If you meditate, you can still be talking to people and be going on.
So, thank you very much - clap for my brother.
Anyone else there?
My brother here wants to tell us the way he will be filled today.
When you are filled with God's Word through meditation, it helps you to obey the Word,
because your heart will not occupy you; instead, you will occupy your heart.
Did you listen to that?
The advantage of this is that it will reset your belief, focus.
Many of us talk too much; we are lying.
This thing will reset your faith, your belief.
Thank you very much.
Who else?
The little girl here.
Are you in that business of meditation now?
Now, you know the meaning of meditation:
Speak to yourself in hymns, Psalms and spiritual songs.
Make melodies in your heart all the time.
Before you know it, you are filled.
This heart is the challenge you have.
Your heart is the one controlling you, directing you
but right now, it is time to take hold of your heart.
"No, my heart - you have been embarrassing me."
Emmanuel.
In order for you to be filled with the Spirit, you need to be grounded in the Word,
so that the Holy Spirit will have something to hold on to.
If you are not grounded in the Word, the Holy Spirit will not have anything to remind you of.
Did you listen to that?
In order to be filled, you have to be grounded in the Word.
You have to be sane in your heart.
If not, the Holy Spirit will have nothing to remind you of.
"Thou shalt not kill" from the Bible - He is the One telling us this.
So please, thank you.
Anyone else?
Give it to the sister there.
Emmanuel.
Since I know what the Holy Spirit means by...
Before, I used to be angry and aggressive to my six kids.
You used to be...?
Aggressive, angry.
This thing has given me heart attack, hypertension, blood pressure.
My daughter said, "Look, if you want to live long, you have to be calm".
Really, I remember the Holy Spirit working for me, since I started meditating.
I remember when daddy brought out this faith bracelet - "take more of me, give me more of You".
Let us see your...
Take more of me, give me more of You, Holy Spirit.
Thank you, clap for her.
Did you listen to that?
When this faith bracelet was given, the language followed - "take more of me, give me more of You".
I have given you another one today: "Locate me in Your mercy...
Locate me in Your favour, locate me in Your mercy...
Take more of me, give me more of You".
Even when I'm praying for you, you continue to do that meditation,
"Locate me in Your favour, locate me in Your mercy".
Thank you, my sister.
Anyone else?
OK, give it to my brother there.
Emmanuel.
It is my first time in The SCOAN.
I listen to Emmanuel TV all the time.
Emmanuel TV has changed my life.
I didn't read the Bible before, until I started watching Emmanuel TV.
When I started watching Emmanuel TV, I saw the man of God preaching,
giving advice that we should be meditating - "Give me more of You, God, take more of me".
I imbibed that caution.
I'm a clinical pharmacist; I have my own clinical pharmacy.
I counsel patients, I see them on a daily basis.
On this occasion, I was in my office attending to patients.
I had imbibed the caution of "Give me more of You, take more of me".
This time I was doing that.
I was attending to a patient and I was meditating, "Give me more of You, take more of me".
Behold!
The mother and the daughter.
After the mother had complained, the daughter followed.
While I was talking, I was meditating, "Give me more of You, take more of me, Lord..."
I then asked the girl, "How are you? What is your name?"
I said, "Shake me".
The moment I shook the hand of this girl, she said, "Leave me! Do you know me
Do you know who I am? You see me small. I'm a big woman".
The mother, sitting next to her, didn't know anything.
In fact, I was shocked.
I was looking, and I said, "Glory be to God. God of Prophet T.B. Joshua has taken me to this realm.
I want to go deeper to the other realm."
Did you listen to that?
You remember what I told you, that the prayer you used to offer -
all this while, you are wasting your time.
The prayer is all about heart, but your prayer is all about your mouth.
You are just wasting your time.
Each time I see people say, "In the name of Jesus...", I say, "Ooo - you are inviting an attack".
Will you reset yourself now and start this meditation - that is the prayer you need now.
As you are sitting, what is going on in your heart?
Ask your neighbour, "What is going on in your heart?
Have you taken hold of your heart?
Are you in charge?
Speak to yourself in Psalms, hymns and spiritual songs.
Make melodies in your heart."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You see what is happening now.
He was meditating in his heart, no one knew what he was saying in his heart,
but mere stretching hand to the little one, "Leave me! I'm this" - she started confessing.
You keep deceiving yourself - you say you are praying.
Those who are not supposed to pray for you are praying for you;
you are better than them but they are praying for you.
Prayer has become a culture, a tradition.
Prayer is not a tradition, it’s as it should be by divine will.
You wake up in the morning, you say, "Let's pray".
Instead of counselling your family first, "Hello. Good morning. What has happened?
What happened yesterday? I corrected you yesterday. I told you not to do this.
I hope you have learnt your lesson from it. OK. What is going on in your school. Please, come on.
The way you look is not right, you keep malice. Please, be cheerful as a Christian.
Do you have any pain? What is worrying you?"
These are counsels you need to give to your family.
After that counselling you will then tell them about Jesus, the Holy Spirit I'm talking about now.
"This is what the Bible says and what Prophet T.B. Joshua also mentioned last Sunday -
You have to speak to yourself with all your heart; speak to yourself – that is the biggest prayer."
Every other prayer is small.
The biggest prayer is to speak to your heart, take hold of your heart,
speak to yourself in Psalms, in hymns, make melodies while you are walking, sleeping, all the time.
Tthat is the greatest prayer that defeats the enemy, that will help you, that will protect you.
That is the prayer!
The one you make today waking up and saying, "In Jesus' name, be rebuked!" - whom are you talking to?
You are wasting your time.
You have seen enough of this prayer.
You can see that nothing...
Thank you, brother. Clap for him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is the best prayer to God?
Can somebody?
Give it to my brother.
The best prayer.
Emmanuel.
The best prayer is the prayer that comes from the heart.
How can the prayer come from the heart?
When you are meditating on the Word of God in your heart, and your heart is connected with God,
that is the best prayer ever.
I have an example.
One day, when I was in the car, I was meditating on the Word of God.
I was in front of the vehicle between two people; the driver and the other one.
Whilst I was meditating on the Word of God, the driver shouted, "Hey!"
Then I shouted, "Jesus!"
Then I found myself outside, standing on my feet.
I don't know how I got there - I was standing outside, while the other people had broken bones.
They stayed in the car, they couldn't come out, the car somersaulted 3 times.
I thank God I shouted "Jesus!" before it happened - and I was standing outside.
But our people today shout "Jesus" after it happened.
I know you.
You shout "Jesus" after nightmare, trouble.
I want to leave you.
Once again - please, be filled.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to have your report; send me an e-mail and let me follow it up.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
This Bible you are carrying without the Holy Spirit is literature.
This Bible you are carrying without the Holy Spirit is history.
It’s not possible for anyone to obey the Word of God without the Holy Spirit.
Not that you will not obey when you say, "Thou shalt not lie".
Without the Holy Spirit you say, "I will not lie again. T.B. Joshua said in his message we should not lie".
You will keep that for one day, two days, three days, four days;
on the fifth day you will become the greatest liar.
You will explode.
That is how far you can go.
But with God all things are possible.
But how far you can go; you keep saying "Thou shalt not lie" -
on the first day you will be conscious of yourself;
you want to lie but you are conscious of yourself, "The Bible says we should not lie".
The second day...
The third day...
What of you, drunkard?
You stop today, stop for five days...
In the dream they will give you to drink; you will finish 10 bottles of beer.
By the time you have taken it so much in your dream, you will wake up.
You are going to the beer parlour to drink.
Without the Holy Spirit, no one can obey the written Word of God.
Tell your neighbour.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT ROBERT BEGIER 27/09/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 04/10/2018